idealware.org 2007-06-30

# Idealware: Privacy Policy

Idealware Privacy Policy  

Last updated Jan 15th, 2006  

Idealware takes privacy issues very seriously. This privacy policy identifies the ways we collect, use and protect personally identifiable information as well as your options for accessing and correcting that information. 

**What personally identifiable information does Idealware collect?**  
In various places on our website, we gather email addresses and other basic contact information for the purpose of allowing people to subscribe to Idealware publications or to allow us to follow up with an evaluation of specific reports or articles.   
We may also gather contact information from individuals who choose to donate to us via our website or to purchase publications. This information allows us to process donations and orders, acknowledge them in a timely manner, and keep donors informed about the impact of their donation. 

We gather survey information about software usage from individuals who agree to participate. This survey data is analyzed in the aggregate and is not linked back to any personally identifiable information. 

Our website may set “cookies” for the purpose of collecting aggregate statistics about the total number of visitors to our website or to ensure that visitors have registered to view restricted publications. We do not store any personally identifiable information in cookies.   

Like most website operators, our web servers create log files. These track data on Internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, Internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, platform type, date/time stamp, and number of clicks to enable us to administer the site, analyze trends, track user movement in the aggregate, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use. Server log files do not contain personally identifiable information. 

Some of our online publications use coded hyperlinks to identify and track personally identifiable information about individuals’ interactions with our website. 

**How does Idealware use personally identifiable information?**  
Idealware uses personal information to send enewsletters and survey invitations to individuals who have specifically opted in to receive them. 

Individuals who register to see specific publications on the Idealware site are not sent enewsletters or invitations for software usage surveys unless they opt in to receive them. These individuals may be sent invitations to evaluate the specific publication for which they registered.  

We also use personally identifiable records of people’s interactions with our online publications as a means for better understanding their interests in our work. At some point in time, this information may be used to personalize the publications. 

Idealware partners with service providers to host our website, provide email service, and other functionalities. Third-party service providers are not permitted to use or share any personally identifiable information that we provide to them. Idealware does not share any of the personally identifiable information we collect with any other outside parties, unless we have received your specific permission to do so or are required to by law. 

**How does Idealware protect personally identifiable information?**  
Idealware takes every precaution to protect our users’ information. When users submit sensitive information via the website, their information is protected both online and off-line.   
When our website asks users to enter sensitive information (such as credit card numbers), that information is encrypted and is protected with the best encryption software in the industry -- Secure Sockets Layer (SSL). 

While we use SSL encryption to protect sensitive information online, we also do everything in our power to protect user information off-line. All of our users’ information, not just the sensitive information mentioned above, is restricted in our offices. Only employees who need the information to perform a specific job are granted access to personally identifiable information. All of our databases are password-protected to ensure that unauthorized users cannot access sensitive data. 

**What choices do I have in interacting with Idealware?**  
You can opt out of receiving communications from us. You may request access to personally identifiable information we collect about you through our electronic communications and you may request corrections to that information. For any of these requests or for more information about our privacy policies and practices, please contact us at [info@idealware.org](mailto:info@idealware.org) or 718-208-8172.   

### Sign Up for Monthly eNews
